자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)
아뇨, 잊지 않고 있습니다
No, we didn't forget about you.
네. 여기 다 있습니다
Yeah. It's all here.
지금 확인해드릴게요
I'm looking at it now.
토마토 소스 캔 두 개
Two cans tomato paste,
파팔 파스타 16온스짜리 한 상자
one 16-ounce box farfalle pasta.
글래드 포스플랙스 쓰레기봉투 한 상자
one box of GLAD Forceflex trash bags.
하나, 둘, 셋, 넷, 캔디 바 네 개
바나나 한 송이요
One, two, three, four candy bars,
and a bunch of bananas.
네, 10분 내로 배달해드리겠습니다
Yeah, he'll be there in ten minutes.
주소 알고 있지, 응?
You know the address, right?
오늘 사탕받기 하러
나가려나봐?
You going out tonight
trick-or-treating?
전 그러기엔 나이가 많은걸요
I think I'm a little old.
무슨, 난 고등학교 시절 내내
할로윈 땐 사탕 받으러 나갔다고
Hell, I went trick-or-treating
all through high school.
5달러 51센트예요
That'll be $5.51.
여기요
Here you go.
- 고마워
- 감사합니다
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
- 즐거운 밤 보내라고
- 손님도요
- You have a good night.
- You too.
저기요
Hi.
이보시오
Hello.
안녕하시오, 실례이오만...
Hello, excuse me.
실례이오만, 음...
불 좀 빌릴 수 있겠소?
Excuse me, um,
do you have a light?
MONK Season 4 Epi. 2
Mr. Monk Goes Home Again
토니 샬롭
(에이드리안 몽크 役)
트레일러 하워드
(나탈리 티거 役)
제이슨 그레이 스탠포드
(랜달 디셔 경위 役)
테드 리바인
(리랜드 스토틀마이어 경감 役)
딕테이션
김철균(kim1047@nate.com)
싱크편집
윤선영(seedyun@nate.com)
한글번역
이재연(vostoc@nate.com)
번역수정
김철균(kim1047@nate.com)
한글교정
이재연(vostoc@nate.com)
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON USA: 2005/07/15
총 사진 몇 장 잘 찍었겠지?
잘했어
Get some good shots of the gun?
Good.
음, 여기 사람들도 좀 찍어둬
혹시 모르니까 말이야
Um, shoot this crowd too.
You never know.
할로윈이 원인이겠죠. 그렇죠?
Halloween. Am I right?
할로윈이 되면 항상
섬뜩한 뭔가가 일어난다고요
Something nasty always
goes down on Halloween.
정말?
Really?
작년 할로윈 때는 무슨 일이 있었는데?
What went down last Halloween?
아무 일도 없었네요
Nothing.
그 이전엔 뭐 하나라도 있었던가?
The one before that?
새로운 전통인가 보죠
It's a new tradition.
할로윈의...
Halloween.
나 이 가게 알아요
I know this store.
맥케이브즈라고 부르곤 했죠
It used to be called McCabes.
여기서 4블록 정도 떨어진 데서 자랐는데
I grew up four blocks away.
After school,
방과 후에 주차장의 바로 이곳으로
아이들이 몰려와서는
all the kids would hang out
right here in the parking lot,
- 음료수를 마시고 음악을 듣곤 했죠
- 재미있었을 것 같네요
- drinking sodas and listening to music.
- That sounds like fun.
오, 그럼요. 아주 재미있었죠
Oh, yeah. It was a lot of fun.
전 길 건너 저쪽에 서서
지켜보곤 했죠
I used to stand over there
across the street.
완벽한 각도였어요
I had a perfect view.
좋은 시절이었어요
Good times.
- 좋은 시절이었어요
- 어서 오게, 몽크
- Good times.
- Hey, Monk.
와 줘서 고마우이
아, 끔찍하니 보지 말아요
Thanks for coming.
Uh, it's kind of ugly.
운전수가 1시 15분쯤에 점심을
해결하러 들렀대
The driver stopped around 1:15 for lunch.
트럭으로 돌아가는 도중에
He's on his way back to the truck
살인자가 나타나서는
운전사의 총을 빼앗았다는군
when the shooter came up,
grabbed his gun.
근거리에서 운전사를
4~5번 쐈어
Shoots him four, maybe five times
point blank range.
운전사가 쓰러졌는데도
계속 쏘고 있었다는군
But he keeps shooting him
even after the guy went down.
오, 맙소사
이 사람 결혼했나요?
Oh, my god.
Was he married?
- 모르겠는데요
- 아이는 있나요?
- I don't know.
- Any kids?
모릅니다, 나탈리
저도 이곳에 방금 도착했거든요
I don't know, Natalie.
I just got here myself.
피해자 총으로 그랬다고요?
With his own gun?
틀림없이 목격자들이 있겠네요
There must've been witnesses.
네, 가게에서 몇 사람들이 봤대요
Yeah, a few people from the store.
백인이고, 어두운 색 머리칼에
파란색 스웨터인지 재킷인지 입었다는군요
Caucasian. Dark hair.
Maybe a blue sweater or jacket.
다시 심문을 해 볼 거예요
We're gonna question them again.
범인이 얼마나 가져갔어요?
How much did he get?
빈 트럭이었어
The truck is empty.
내가 알고 있기로는 말이야
That's all I know.
야, 저리 가
Hey, get out of there.
가! 호, 호, 호!
Go. Ho, ho, ho!
꺼져!
Get!
난 비둘기가 싫어
날개 달린 쥐라니까
I hate pigeons.
Like rats with wings.
방어흔이 없네요
No defensive wounds.
몸싸움은 없었대요?
Was there a struggle?
어떻게, 어떻게 범인이 총을
뺏었을까요? / 좋은 질문이야
- How did, how did this guy get the gun?
- That's a good question.
검시관이 곧 도착한다는군
그에게 물어볼 수 있을 거야
The M.E.'s gonna be here in a minute.
We can ask him.
이게 뭐죠?
What's this?
오, 여기 버려진지 얼마 안됐네요
오물이 안 묻었잖아요
Oh, this hasn't been here long.
It's clean.
클로브 담배일세
That's a Clove cigarette.
인도네시아 산이지
사람들이 담배 끊으려고 할 때 핀다네
They make them in Indonesia.
People use them to try to quit smoking.
- 효과는 없지만 말이야
- 운전사 것일까요?
- They don't work.
- Driver's?
운전사 담배는 다른 거잖아
The driver has his own.
범인의 것 같네요
I'm thinking it's the shooter's.
음, 이걸 추적해보게
Well, run that down.
- 이걸 파는 모든 가게에 알아봐
- 여보세요
- Every store that sells those.
- Hello.
아뇨, 샤로나는 그만 뒀어요
No, Sharona's not here anymore.
음, 1년 전쯤부터요
Uh, about a year ago.
무슨 일이 있던 건지는 모르겠어요
뉴저지로 이사갔다네요
Well, I don't know what happened.
She moved to New Jersey.
선생님, 저도 무슨 일인지 몰라요
샤로나에게 물어보셔야겠네요
Sir, I don't know what happened.
You'd have to ask her.
누구신가요?
Who is this?
몽크 씨, 형님이라네요
Mr. Monk, it's your brother.
앰브로즈요?
Ambrose?
어, 받을 수 없어요
I can't. I, uh...
나중에 다시 건다고 전해주세요
나 바쁘다고 전해주세요
Tell him I'll call him back.
Tell him I'm busy.
아버님이 전화하셨대요
Your father called.
우리 아버지가요?
My father?
집으로 오고 계시다는데요
He's coming home.
됐지? 여기서 사탕받기 하는 거야
See? You can trick-or-treat here.
내가 같이 가줄게
I'll go with you.
아, 엄마랑 같이 가는 사탕받기라...
퍽도 재미있겠네요
Oh, fun. Trick-or-treating with your mom.
아주 말 안 듣는 나이예요
11살부터 25살까지죠
She's at that impossible age,
between 11 and 25.
왜요? 괜찮아요?
What? You okay?
아주 오랜만에 아버지를
만나는 건데 뭐라고 말하죠?
What do I say to him
after all these years?
음, 이렇게요
You say,
"안녕하세요, 아버지
보고 싶었어요"
"Hello, dad. I missed you."
안돼요
No.
안돼요, 난 그렇게 말 못해요
No, I can't say that.
왜 아버지가 그렇게 떠나셨던 거죠?
Why did he leave just like that?
나 때문이에요
It was my fault.
내가 아버질 미치게 만들었거든요
I drove him crazy.
아버지가 그러셨어요?
He said that?
아뇨
No.
근데 어떻게 알아요?
Then how do you know?
난, 알아요
난... 그냥 안다고요
I, I know. I, I just know.
몽크 씨, 자책하지 말아요
Mr. Monk, you can't blame yourself.
정말 내 탓이 아닐까요?
You wanna bet?
줄리, 좋아. 얌전히 굴어, 알았지?
Julie, okay, be nice, okay?
엄마가 얘기했던 거 기억하지?
Remember what we talked about?
몽크 씨 형님은 아프시단 거
광장 공포증이 있으셔
Mr. Monk's brother's ill.
He's agoraphobic.
알아요. 절대 집 밖으로 안 나오신다면서요
I know. He never leaves his house.
한 번 나왔단다
34년 동안 딱 한 번
He left once.
Once in 34 years.
- 적어도 나오시긴 했군요
- 그래, 집에 불이 났지
- At least he left.
- Well, the house was on fire.
그래서 내가 끌고 나왔단다
I had to drag him out.
- 에이드리안
- 아빠하고 통화했다며?
Adrian.
You talked to him?
내가 아빠 돌아오실 거라고 했지?
I told you he'd be back.
업무 차 여기 오셨다는구나
He's in town on a business trip.
정확히 여덟 시 정각에 들르시겠대
He said he'd be here at 8 o'clock sharp.
넌 포기했지만
난 포기하지 않았어
You gave up.
But I never gave up.
I never gave up. Never.
난 포기하지 않았다고. 한번도
사탕받기 하러 온 거니?
Are you trick-or-treating?
아냐, 아냐. 이쪽은 나탈리로
내 새로운 조수야
No. No.
This is Natalie, my new assistant.
형이랑 통화했었지
You spoke on the phone.
만나 뵙게 되어 기쁩니다
Enchanter de vous rencontrer.
전 앰브로즈 몽크입니다
에이드리안의 형이죠
I'm Ambrose Monk, Adrian's brother.
- 앰브로즈 몽크입니다
- 네, 알고 있어요
- Ambrose Monk.
- Yes, I know.
만나 뵙게 되어
매우 기쁘군요, 앰브로즈
Very nice to meet you, Ambrose.
네 / 어...
Yes. / Uh...
이쪽은 제 딸이에요, 줄리죠
this is my daughter, Julie.
의상이 맘에 드는구나
너는, 너는 심장 전문의구나
I like your costume.
You're, you're a cardiologist.
- 의사인데요
- 아냐, 심장 전문의야
- I'm a doctor.
- No, you're a cardiologist.
봐라, 이 청진기에는 오목하게 생긴
자체 증폭기가 설치되어 있지 않니
You see, that stethoscope has
a built-in concave amplifier.
스테트론이라고 하는 거란다
It's called a stethron.
심장 전문의가 심장의 이상 음을
들을 때 사용하는 거지
Cardiologists use it
to listen for heart murmurs.
- 그럼, 전 심장 전문의가 맞겠네요
- 뭐 아무렴 어떠니
- Guess I'm a cardiologist.
- It's all right.
나도 잘 몰랐던 적이 있단다
I made a mistake once.
들어와, 들어오세요
Come, come in.
와, 무시무시하네요
매년 할로윈 때마다 이렇게 하세요?
Wow. This is spooky.
Do you do this every year for Halloween?
이렇게 하냐고, 뭘?
Do what?
아, 아무것도 아녜요
Um, nothing.
이건 다 사용 설명서네요?
All these instruction manuals.
네, 형이 만든 거예요
Yes, Ambrose wrote them.
그게 형의 직업이죠
That's what he does.
와, 앰브로즈 씨, 틀림없이
집 주변기기들 다루는 데 능숙하시겠네요
Wow, Ambrose, you must
be pretty handy around the house.
맞아요, 엄마랑 제가 말리부
제니 방갈로를 조립할 때
Yeah, you should've been there
when we were putting together
my Malibu jenny bungalow.
아저씨가 계셨으면 좋았을 뻔 했네요
우리 엄만 다섯 시간이나 걸렸거든요
- It took my mom five hours.
- I'm not surprised.
별로 놀랄 일도 아니지
조립 설명서를 마이크 고든이 썼거든
Mike Gordon wrote that one.
그치는 바보야
He's a hack.
그 사람은 0.75인치 고정용 나사와
0.5인치 나무 볼트도 구별 못 하거든요
The man can't tell the difference
between a 3/4 inch retaining screw
and a half inch lag bolt.
농담 아니에요
I'm not kidding.
그 사람 정말 그런 실수를 했다고요
He actually made that mistake.
그 인간이 니즈-엠-유 상을
받은 게 아직도 안 믿긴다니까
Still can't believe
he won the Niz-em-ew award.
니즈-엠 뭐?
Niz-em what?
전국 사용 설명서 작가들의 모임 말이야
National society of
instruction manual writers.
아, 그래
Oh. Right.
난 거기서 다섯 번이나 상을 받았다고
I've won five of them.
- 볼 수 있어요?
- 아니
- Can we see one?
- No.
여기 없거든
They're not here.
우편배달은 안 해주겠대
They won't mail them.
음, 그래도 상을 탔다는 게
중요한 거죠
Well, at least you won them.
That's the important thing.
누가 왔는데, 형
It's the door, Ambrose.
- 누가 왔다니까
- 실례하겠소
- The door.
- Excuse me.
- 사탕 주세요!
- Trick-or-treat!
기다려라. 기다려
아직 안 돼
Wait. Wait. Not yet.
'사탕 주세요'라는
너희들의 요구를 받아들였다
Trick-or-treat.
I've accepted your terms,
그 말은 즉, 우리가 암묵적인
계약을 맺는다는 거지
which means we now
have an implied contract.
이 사탕을 받아간다는 건
By accepting this treat,
너희들이 나 또는 이 집에 대해
지금 그리고 앞으로도
you are in effect promising to refrain
from committing any tricks
어떠한 장난도 치지 않겠다고
사실상 약속한다는 거다
against me or this property
now or in the future.
다른 질문 있니?
Are there any questions?
- 네. 땅콩 바 있어요?
- 이 그릇 안에 있는 게 전부 그거란다
- Yeah. Do you have any peanut chews?
- There's only what's in the bowl.
자, 한 사람 앞에 하나씩이다
알겠니?
Now, one per customer, all right?
좀 나아 보여요?
Better?
아, 네. 전엔 좀 어수선했죠
Oh, yeah. It was cluttered before.
뭐하는 거니?
What are you doing?
너, 너 거기 들어가면 안 된다
You, you can't go in there.
거기 들어가면 안 돼
You cannot go in there.
죄송해요
몰랐어요
I'm sorry.
I didn't know.
- 무슨 일이에요?
- 거, 거긴 우리 아버지의 서재야
- What's going on?
- That, that is, that's dad's study.
우리, 우리한테
거긴 출입금지 구역이라고요
We're, we're, we're
not allowed in there.
출입금지요?
Not allowed?
네. 내가 열두 살 때 딱 한 번
들어가 봤다가 붙잡혔어요
Yes. Dad caught me in there once
when I was 12.
그래서 어떻게 됐는데요, 앰브로즈 씨?
What happened, Ambrose?
벌로 외출금지가 됐죠
He grounded me.
30년 동안이나요?
For 30 years?
괜찮다, 줄리
It's all right, Julie.
형, 뭐가 그리 큰일이야?
Ambrose, what's the big deal?
이 방안 좀 둘러보자
We'll just take a look around.
우린 이제 다 컸잖아, 그렇지?
We're adults, right?
너 거기 들어가면, 말할 거야
You go in there, I will tell.
- 안 그러는 게 좋을걸
- 할 거야! 말할 거야
- You better not.
- I will! I'm, I'm telling.
좋아, 그럼 난 면도용구 세트에
대해서 말할 거야
Well, then I'm telling him
about the shaving kit.
안 돼! 에이드리안, 들어가면 안 돼
Don't! Adrian, don't go in there.
아버지가 둔 상태
그대로여야 한단 말이야
It has to be exactly
the way he left it.
- 여긴 아버지의 서재라고
- 알겠어
- It's daddy's study.
- Okay.
그래. 안 들어갈게
Okay. I'm not going in.
실례할게요, 나탈리
어, 줄리도
Excuse me, Natalie, uh, Julie.
사탕 받으러 애들이 와서요
I, I have trick-or-treaters.
몇 살이니?
How old are you?
나에겐 규칙이 있는데
14살 이상은 안 준다
Because I have a rule,
no one older than 14.
한 사람 앞에 하나씩이야
Only one per customer.
뭐 하는 거니?
What are you doing?
한 사람 앞에 하나씩이라니까
내 말 들었니?
Only one per customer.
Did you hear what I said?
안 돼, 안 돼
한 사람 앞에 하나씩이라니까
No. No, only one per customer.
썩 꺼지지 못해!
Get out of here!
이봐!
Hey!
- 썩 물러가요!
- 야! 야!
- Get out of here!
- Hey! Hey!
앰브로즈, 괜찮아요?
Ambrose, are you okay?
앰브로즈, 움직일 수 있어요?
Ambrose, can you move?
그 녀석이 하나 이상 가져갔나요?
Did he get more than one piece?
- 정말 괜찮은 거예요?
- 네
- Are you sure you're okay?
- Yeah.
당신을 공격한 남자의 키가
5피트였다고요?
The man who attacked you
was 5 feet tall.
맞아요
That's right.
목에 볼트가 꽂힌
녹색 가면을 썼고요
And he wore a green mask
with a bolt through the neck.
뭐라고 말했나요?
Did he say anything?
"크르르"라고 하던걸요
He said, "Grr."
아녜요. 아녜요
그건...
No, no, no, no.
It was...
프랑켄슈타인이라고 적게
Write down Frankenstein.
아니죠, 프랑켄슈타인이 아니라
No, it wasn't Frankenstein.
프랑켄슈타인이 만든 괴물이죠
It was Frankenstein's monster.
프랑켄슈타인은 괴물을 만들어낸
과학자의 이름이라고요
Frankenstein is the name of the
scientist who created the monster.
그건 중요한 문제가 아닙니다
It doesn't really matter.
경감님, 프랑켄슈타인이라고
말하면 안돼요
Captain, you can't
just say Frankenstein,
모두에게 혼란을 가져올 거예요
it'll confuse everybody.
알겠습니다. 프랑켄슈타인이 만든
괴물이라고 적게
Okay, write down
Frankenstein's monster.
그 작자가 공원을 향해 남쪽으로
뛰어가는 것을 봤으니
I saw the guy running south
towards the park. Maybe he's there.
아마 공원에 있을 거예요
음, 아마도 마리화나를
피운 후에 배고팠던 고등학생일 거예요
Look, it's probably just some high
school kid with the munchies.
제 생각은 달라요
정장구두를 신고 있었거든요
I don't think so.
He was wearing dress shoes.
이탈리아 제, 피저리어스요
They were Italian, Forzieris.
너도 봤지, 그렇지?
You noticed that, right?
난 잘 모르는 상표야
- I'm not familiar.
- They're imported.
그건 수입품으로
한 켤레에 420달러나 한다고
They cost about $420 a pair.
마리화나 피우는 고등학생 녀석이
신을 법한 신발이 아니죠
It's not exactly something
a high school kid
with munchies would be wearing.
좋아요. 그럼, 마리화나 피우는
부잣집 고등학생 녀석이라고 하죠
Okay, it was a rich high
school kid with the munchies.
음, 앰브로즈 씨, 캔디가
쏟아진 건 정말 유감이지만
Look, I'm really sorry
that your candy got spilled,
이 사건은 지금 우리에게
급한 게 아니에요
but this isn't a priority
for us right now.
아마 들으셨겠지만
You might have heard that
there was an armored car driver shot
just down the street.
저 아래에서 현금 수송 차량
운전사가 총에 맞아 죽었거든요
맞아요. 맞아요
어떻게 되어가고 있어요?
Right. Right.
How is that going?
음, 아직은 아무것도 없지만
Uh, nothing yet.
But get this.
운전사는 비번이었으니
그 트럭은 애초부터 비어있었단 거죠
The driver was off duty.
The truck was empty from the start.
비어있었다고?
It was empty?
그래, 범인이 사전 조사를
제대로 안 했나봐
Yeah, I guess the shooter
didn't do his homework.
그건 그렇고, 그 식료품점의
계산원이랑 얘기해보러 갈 건데
Anyway, we're off to question
the cashier at the grocery store.
자네도 갈 텐가?
도움이 될 거 같아서
Do you want to come?
I could use the help.
안 돼요. 아버지가...
I can't. My father.
아, 맞다. 이해하네
Oh, yeah. I understand.
잘 되길 바라네
I hope that goes well for you.
내일 전화할게
I'll call you tomorrow.
가세, 디셔
Come on, lieutenant.
뭐하시는 겁니까, 경위님?
What are you doing, lieutenant?
아, 전 그냥...
Oh, I'm just.../ Sorry, you can't take that.
I don't have any extra.
죄송합니다만 가져가시면 안 돼요
여분이 없거든요
- It's just candy.
- I know how much I need.
- 그냥 사탕이잖아
- 딱 필요한 만큼만 가지고 있어요
과학적으로 분석한 결과죠
Every year, I have it down to a science
매년 기상 상황
최근의 인구 통계 자료
based on current weather conditions,
recent census data,
작년의 할로윈 때의
캔디 소모량들을 바탕으로 말이죠
and the demand from previous Halloweens.
작년엔 단 하나의 캔디만 남기고
할로윈을 마쳤다고요
Last year, I ended up
with just one extra candy bar.
음, 앰브로즈 씨
그거, 음...
Well, Ambrose, that's, um...
그거 참...
That's very...
그게 참 뭐하는 짓거린지 모르겠군요
I don't know what the hell that is.
어서 오게, 디셔
스니커즈 바 하나 사줄게
Come on, lieutenant,
I'll buy you a snickers bar.
에이드리안, 어...
잠깐 얘기 좀 할 수 있을까?
Adrian, could I, could I talk to you?
응, 잠깐만
Yeah, one second.
이거 중요한 거야
It's important.
뭔데?
What?
여기서 말고
Out here.
멈춰. 제발
Stop it. I mean it.
멈추라고
Stop.
좋아, 뭔데?
Okay, what?
이리로
This way.
아, 싫어 / 그래야 아무도 우리가
하는 얘기를 못 듣지
No, no. / So nobody can hear
what we're doing.
좀 먼지가 많네
It's a little dusty.
좋아. 어서 와
All right, come on.
얼른
Come on.
오, 맙소사
Oh, god.
좋아
Okay.
그래, 좋아
Okay. Okay.
너하고 나탈리 말이야...
Are you and Natalie...
뭐?
What?
서로 사귀어?
Involved?
뭐?
What?
아냐. 아냐
No. No.
아냐. 아냐. 도대체 왜
나한테 그런 걸 묻지?
No. No. Why, why
would you even ask me that?
음, 트루디가 죽은지도 8년이 지났잖아
Well, it's been eight years since Trudy.
그렇지!
Exactly!
겨우 8년밖에 안 됐지
It's only been eight years.
넌 홀아비고
나탈리는 과부야
You're a widower.
She's a widow.
그리고 난 네가 여자들과
어떻게 지내는지 안단다
And I know how you are
with the ladies.
고등학교 때 그 여자애들...
난 기억하고 있지
I remember, in high school,
those girls...
너에게 전화를 걸어서
calling you on the phone,
같이 얘기하다가
talking to you on the phone,
너에게 찬탄을 보냈던
여자들, 응? / 형, 형...
- complimenting you, huh?
- Ambrose, Ambrose...
전부 선생님들이었어
those were my teachers.
그래서?
So?
플레건 부인은 뭐였는데?
What about Mrs. Flagan?
내 말 맞지?
Yeah?
나탈리는 내 조수야
Natalie works for me.
완전히 직업적인 사이라고, 알겠어?
Strictly professional, okay?
나탈리가 데이트하는 사람은?
Is she seeing anybody else?
왜? 왜 묻는데?
Why? Why?
그냥
No reason.
사탕 주세요!
Trick-or-treat!
오, 놀랍게 분장했네들
맘에 드는구나. 자, 여기 있다
Oh, you guys look amazing.
I love it. Here you go.
- 안녕, 줄리
- 안녕, 프랭키
- Hey, Julie.
- Hey, Frankie.
프랭키는 같은 반 친구예요
Frankie's in my homeroom.
넌 벌써 사탕받기를 다
마친 거니?
So have you gone
trick-or-treating yet?
- 그게 아니라면, 같이 가자
- 제발요, 엄마?
- If not, you can come with us.
- Please, mom?
좋아. 여덟 시까지 돌아와야 해
꼭 붙어다니고
Okay. Be back by 8:00.
Stick together.
너희들 도로 이쪽에서만
다녀야 한다, 알겠지?
You guys stay on this side
of the freeway, all right?
그건 그렇고
여기 엄마 전화기 갖고 가
Okay...
here's my cell phone.
그리고 엄마가 검사하기 전까진
아무거나 먹지 마! / 안녕, 엄마
And don't eat anything
until I inspect it! / Bye, mom.
잘 했어요. 고마워요
Good job. Thank you.
전에는 이 사람을 본 적 없나요?
And you've never seen this guy before?
가게에서나 주차장에서
어슬렁거리는 거라도요?
In the store?
Hanging around the parking lot?
못 본거 같아요
I don't think so.
- 근데 전 많은 사람들과 마주치거든요
- 물론 그러시겠죠
- But I see a lot of faces.
- Sure.
키퍼 서덜랜드 같군요
It looks like Kiefer Sutherland.
응, 그런 것도 같네
Yeah, I guess it does.
키퍼 서덜랜드는 아니었죠?
It wasn't Kiefer Sutherland, was it?
네, 아니었어요
No, sir.
좋습니다. 이거 영수증인데
All right, here's a receipt.
아가씨 금전등록기에서 나온 겁니다
범인 거 맞죠, 그렇죠?
This is from your cash register.
This is him, right?
89센트짜리 여덟 개로군요
Eight items at 89 cents.
네, 형사님. 캔디 바 여덟 개를 샀어요
Yes, sir. Eight candy bars.
캔디 바 여덟 개라고요?
Eight candy bars?
정말 키퍼 서덜랜드처럼 보이는데요
It really looks like Kiefer Sutherland.
반장님, 그게 말이죠
You know, maybe we should,
이걸 배포하기 전에
전단지 밑에다가
before we distribute it,
write across the bottom,
"키퍼 서덜랜드 아님"이라고
써줘야 할 거 같아요
"Not Kiefer Sutherland"
서덜랜드 씨가 우리 때문에
귀찮은 일을 당할지도 모르잖아요
just so that we don't
disturb Mr. Sutherland.
- 거 참 좋은 생각이로구먼
- 그렇죠?
- That's a really good idea.
- You think so?
아니
No.
자, 하던 얘기로 다시 돌아갑시다
Let's do this again.
그 사람이 돈을 내고 걸어나갔다는 거죠?
So he pays you, then he walks out.
잠시 후에 총 소리를 들었다는 거고요
A minute later, you hear shots.
그래서 창가로 가서 그 남자가
운전사를 쏘고 있는 걸 목격했고요
You run to the window and
see this guy shooting the driver.
네
Yeah.
그리고 범인이 트럭 뒤를
들여다보더니
And then he looks
in the back of the truck,
비어있으니까 도망갔다는 거죠?
sees it's empty, and he takes off.
아뇨, 형사님. 범인은 트럭 뒤를
들여다본 적이 없어요
No, sir. He never looked
in the back of the truck.
정말입니까?
Really.
- 뭐하시는 거야?
- 나중에 보면 알아
What's he doing?
You'll see.
취한 거 아냐?
Is he drunk?
아냐, 생각 중이셔
No, he's thinking.
됐다
Okay.
자, 분명히 그 사람은 너희를
한참 동안 따라다녔던 거야
Now, he must have been
following you all quite a while.
누가 그 사람이 어디로
달아났는지 말해줄 수 있니?
Anybody tell me
which way he ran off?
저쪽으로 갔어요
He went that way.
해밀턴 가에서 왼쪽으로
도는 걸 봤어요
I saw him turn left on Hamilton street.
환각이라도 일으킨 건 아니지?
You sure you weren't hallucinating?
몽크 씨, 얘는 11살이에요
Mr. Monk, he's 11 years old.
진짜 히피가 아니라고요
He's not a real hippie.
제 거도 도둑맞았어요
I got mine stolen, too.
20분전에요
About 20 minutes ago.
제 것도요
Mine, too.
좋다, 그럼 프랑켄슈타인한테
캔디를 도둑맞은 애들은
Okay, I want all of you who had
your candy stolen by Frankenstein
여기에 서고
나머지는 저쪽에 서 보렴
to stand over here
and the others stand over here.
- 자, 얼른
- 그래, 어서
- Let's go.
- Okay, come on.
여기. 그래, 좋아
Here. All right, here.
너희는 여기
You here.
And you others.
잘했다
Good.
그런데 왜 너희는 뺏기고
So why you...
너희는 안 뺏겼을까?
not you?
왜 너희는 뺏기고...
And why you...
너희는 안 뺏겼을까?
not you?
아마 그 사람이 당수를
무서워한 것 아닐까요?
Maybe he's afraid of karate.
아니면 해적을 무서워했을 수도 있어요
Or maybe he's afraid of pirates.
아냐, 어리석은 소리다
No, that's just stupid.
이중에 우리 형 집에 들렀던
사람들은 몇 명이니?
How many of you stopped
by my brother's house?
오크뷰 끝쪽에 있는 큰 회색 집 말이다
The big gray house
near the end of Oakview?
절대 밖으로 나오지 않는
특별한 분이 사는 집 말씀하시는 거예요?
You mean where the special man
lives who never comes out?
그래. 맞아
Yeah. That's right.
특별한 사람이 사는 곳 말이다
Where the special man lives.
몇 명이...
How many...
앰브로즈 집에 들렀던 아이들의
사탕만 뺏어갔다고요?
He's only taking candy from kids
who went to Ambrose's house?
- 무슨 일인 거죠?
- 모르겠어요
- What's going on?
- I don't know.
모르겠어요
I don't know.
잠깐만요. 저건...
Wait a minute, it's...
뭐예요?
What?
- 아니에요
- 뭔데요?
No. / What?
설마...
No.
클로브 담배예요
It's a Clove cigarette.
살인 현장에 있던 것과 같은 거군요
Like the one at the murder scene.
이번엔 누구였는데?
Who was it this time?
흡혈귀? 늑대 인간?
Dracula one? The Werewolf?
아뇨, 아뇨. 프랑켄슈타인이었어요
No, no, it was Frankenstein.
- 프랑켄슈타인이 만든 괴물이라니까
- 프랑켄슈타인이 만든 괴물이요
- Frankenstein's monster.
음, 그 미친 창조물을 막을 것은
아무 것도 없군요
Well, there's just no
stopping that crazy creature.
캔디를 원하는데
아무 캔디나가 아니고
He wants candy.
And not just any candy.
당신의 캔디를 원하는 거요
He wants your candy.
맞아요. 이 집에서 나온
캔디에만 관심을 보이더라고요
That's right, he's only
interested in candy from this house.
저도 그 이유가 몹시 궁금하군요
You know, I can't help but wonder why.
해답은 여기 있어요
바로 우리 앞에 있다고요
The answer is here.
It is right in front of us.
그리고 그 총격 사건과 이 사건이
관련이 있다는 말이지?
And you're saying that this is somehow
connected to the armored car thing.
난 이 캔디들을 전부
비치스 마켓에서 샀어요
Well, I bought all this candy
at Beach's market.
배달해줬죠 / 거기가 바로
운전사가 죽은 곳이잖아요, 그렇죠?
They deliver. / And that's where
the driver was killed, right?
하나 더, 애들이 습격당한 곳에서
이걸 발견했어요
Plus, I found this
where the kids were attacked.
클로브 담배예요
It's a Clove cigarette.
제가 이걸 조사해봤는데요
흔한 거더군요
Actually, I researched these.
They're common.
이 지역에서만 150곳에서 판다고요
150 stores in this area sell them.
좋아, 그러니까 이 사건들이
관련이 있다는 거군
Okay, you're saying
that there is a connection.
난 여기 있으니 날 납득시켜 보게
I'm here. Convince me.
이 도시에서 살인범을 찾느라
혈안이 되어 있는 경찰들이
Why would a killer who every cop
in this city is looking for,
왜 어린 아이가 캔디 빼앗긴 사건에
매달려야 하는지 말이야
hang around to steal candy from children?
우린 모르겠는데요
We don't know.
모른다고요?
You don't know.
나 사탕받기 하러 나가도 돼요?
Can I go trick-or-treating or not?
안 된다. 오늘 밤은 안 된다, 아가야
No, not tonight, sweetie.
약속하셨잖아요
잠깐만이라도 해보고 싶다고요
You promised.
I only got to go a little bit.
아가야, 저 밖에는 미친 사람이 있잖니
Honey, there is a nut out there.
지금 네가 나갈 수 있는 유일한 방법은
경찰 아저씨랑 같이 나가는 것뿐이다
The only way you can go now
is with a police escort.
디셔 경위님
Lieutenant Disher.
- 음?
- 저랑 사탕받기 하러 나가요
- Hmm?
- Come trick-or-treating with me.
어, 난 안돼. 그게...
Oh, I don't, uh...
가도 돼요?
Can I?
아니
No.
에이드리안, 네가 같이
나가주지그래? / 뭐라고?
- Adrian, why don't you go with her?
- What?
나탈리가 나랑 여기 남아있으면 돼
Natalie can stay here with me.
내가 준비하는 걸 도와줄 거야
And help me get ready.
좋은 생각이에요, 그렇죠?
That's such a good idea, right?
할로윈 복장이라고 보기엔
좀 그러네요
It's not much of a costume, is it?
천만에
Sure, it is.
난 안전 순찰 경관이야
I'm a safety patrol officer.
얘, 얘, 기다려!
Hey, hey, wait!
신호가 바뀌면 건너야지
녹색으로 바뀌면 말이다!
Cross at the green,
not in-between!
아직도 이 옷이 맞다니 놀라워요
It's amazing it still fits you.
마지막으로 입었던 때가 언제예요?
초등학교 3학년 때예요?
When was the last time you wore it?
Third grade?
대학교 때였어
College.
오, 사진 몇 장이 있네요
Oh, I found some pictures.
I hope you don't mind. / No, no.
- 실례가 된 건 아니죠?
- 괜찮아요
아버님이세요?
Is that your father?
네, 아버님하고 앰브로즈요
Oh, that's him and Ambrose.
당신 이름을 따서
거북이 이름을 지은 거예요?
He named the turtle after you?
거북이 이름을 따서 제 이름을 지으셨죠
He named me after the turtle.
오, 앰브로즈
Oh, Ambrose.
오, 이거 맘에 드네요
아주 행복해 보여요
Oh, I like this one.
You look so happy.
엄마는 우리가 절대로 웃지 않아서
매우 걱정하셨거든요
Mom was worried about us
because we never laughed.
그래서 우리에게 연습시키셨어요
So she made us practice.
훈련 중에 찍은 거예요
That's us practicing.
그래서 지금은 웃을 수 있죠
So now I can laugh.
그래야 한다면 말이죠
If I have to.
이건 언제 찍은 거예요?
What about this one?
아버지가 떠나시기 하루 전에
찍은 거예요
That was taken the day before he left.
저 때문에 떠나셨어요
He left because of me.
제가 아버지를 졸졸 따라다니며
미치게 만들었죠
I was driving him crazy,
clinging to him.
전 도움 없이는 아무것도
못했거든요
I was too needy.
몽크 씨는 자기 때문에
떠나신 거라던데요
Mr. Monk says it was because of him.
Nah, he's just saying that
to make me feel better.
아녜요, 제 기분을 무마해주려고
그렇게 말하는 것뿐이에요
저 때문이었어요
It was me.
길스트랩이라...
Gilstrap.
- 재미있는 이름이네요
- 그래. 몇 시니?
- That's a funny name.
- Yeah. What time is it?
음, 7시 50분이에요
Um, 10 to 8.
- 여기만 들렀다 집에 가자꾸나
- 안 돼요. 두어 집만 더 들러요
- We gotta get home after this.
- No. Just a couple more houses.
- 사탕 주세요
- Trick-or-treat.
안녕. 의사 선생님께서 오셨구나
Hello. We have a doctor in the house.
저는 심장 전문의예요
I'm a cardiologist.
그리고 당신은 교통안전 소년단이고요
And you're a safety boy.
전 안전 순찰 경관인데요
I'm a safety patrol officer.
그래요, 어쨌든 둘 다 멋져 보이는군요
Well, I think you both look wonderful.
고맙지만 괜찮습니다
알레르기가 있거든요
No, thanks. I'm allergic.
- 초콜릿에요?
- 아뇨, 부인
To chocolate?
No, ma'am.
전 밤새 접시에 담겨서
여러 사람이 주물럭거렸던
I'm allergic to food that's
been sitting in a bowl all night
음식에 알레르기가 있는 거랍니다
and that other people
have been touching.
아, 그래요. 난 초콜릿이 좋은데...
Oh, well, I love chocolate.
매일 밤 잠자리에 들기 전에
넵튠 바 하나씩은 꼭 먹죠
I have to have a neptune bar
every night before I go to bed
안 그러면 잠이 안 오거든요
or I can't sleep.
뭐, 다들 기이한 버릇이 하나씩
있잖아요, 그렇죠?
Well, I guess we all have
our little quirks, don't we?
그렇다고 생각해요
I suppose we do.
어쨌든 감사합니다
Well, thank you very much.
길 건널 때 조심하거라
Be careful crossing the street.
뭐 당신한테는 말할 필요 없겠죠?
I guess I don't have to tell you that.
아마 이게 좀 빠른 거겠죠
Maybe it's fast.
세상에서 제일 정확한
시계 중에 하난데요
It's one of the most
accurate clocks in the world.
제가 이 시계의 설명서를 썼죠
I wrote the manual for it.
금방 올 거예요
They'll be here.
나탈리, 음...
Natalie, uh...
뭐 좀 물어봐도 돼요?
Can I ask you something?
음, 만약에...
Would you ever, uh...
그러니까, 어...
consider, uh...
데이트 상대로 저 같은 사람 어때요?
딱 집어서 말하자면...
going out with someone like me
or to be more specific...
저는요?
물론 우리가 실제로 나갈 순 없죠
Me? Of course, we can't
actually go out.
제 말은, 밖으로 나갈 수 없다는 거예요
I mean, we can't go outside.
그렇지만 이 집 안이라면
어디든 갈 수 있잖아요
But we can go anywhere else.
고마워요, 앰브로즈
Thank you, Ambrose.
고마워요
Thank you.
그런데 그건...
But it's...
그건 까다로운 문제군요
it's complicated.
아, 알겠어요. 말 취소할게요
Okay. I understand. Withdrawn.
그런 말 절대
못 들은 걸로 해주세요
I never said it.
It never happened.
얼음, 얼음 좀 가져올게요
아버진 얼음이 많은 걸 좋아하세요
I'll, I'll get the ice.
My father likes a lot of ice.
전 아버지가 얼음을 쨍 하고
부딪히는 걸 좋아하셨단 걸 기억해요
I remember he, he
used to like clink it.
앰브로즈 씨, 앉아보세요
Ambrose, sit down.
제발요
Please.
제가 당신과 데이트를
할 수 없는 이유는...
I can't go out with you because...
제가 몽크 씨의 조수라서예요
I work for your brother.
아시겠지만, 관계가
복잡해질 수도 있잖아요
You know, it would just get messy.
이해해주시리라 믿어요
You can understand that.
그래요
Yeah.
하지만 언젠가 제가
다른 직업을 갖게 되면
But if I ever have another job someday,
저한테 다시 물어봐 주시면 좋겠어요
I hope you'll ask me again.
정말요?
Really?
그러니까 지금 거절하진 않은 거죠?
So you're not saying no?
그건, 음...
That's like a...
어쩌면 이라는 거죠?
a maybe.
어쩌면 이라고 답하신 거죠?
You're saying maybe.
네, 어쩌면요
I'm saying maybe.
아버지께 말씀드려도 될까요?
Can I tell my father?
그러니까 우리가 언젠가
데이트를 하게 될 거라고요
That we, we might have a date someday?
그럼요
Sure.
아버지께서 좋아하실 것 같아요
I think he'd like that.
오, 맙소사, 이게 뭐예요?
Oh, my, what is it?
엄마 휴대폰 가지고 나왔지?
Did you bring your mom's cell phone?
어이, 몽크
Hey, Monk.
그 옷, 할로윈이어서 입고 있는 거지?
I hope that's your costume.
전 안전 순찰 경관이에요
I'm a safety patrol officer.
잘 어울리는군
Good for you.
뭐가 그리 중요하다는 건가?
So what's so important?
이번엔 뭐한테 당했대요?
마틴 루터 킹 가에 삼총사 나타났대요?
What'd they get this time?
Three musketeers, milky way.
그건 비둘기잖아요
It's a pigeon.
음, 이거 낯익지 않으세요?
Well, does he look familiar?
낯익지 않느냐고?
Does he look familiar?
가까이서 보세요
Take a closer look.
살인 사건 현장에 있던
경감님이 쫓으신 비둘기잖아요
At the murder scene,
you kept shooing it away.
이게 바로 그 비둘기예요
This is that same pigeon.
- 몽크, 오늘 하루가 힘들었나 보군
- 경감님, 이게 그 비둘기라니까요
- Monk, you've had a tough night.
- Captain, this is the same pigeon.
전 그 비둘기 등에 다섯 개의
갈색 점이 있던 게 기억나요
I remember it had five
little brown spots on its back
어떻게 그걸 기억했냐면
because I remember thinking
그 점들을 보고 카시오페이아
별자리가 연상됐거든요
that it reminded me
of the constellation Cassiopeia.
봐. 보이지?
Look. You see it?
- 보라니까!
- 알겠네. 알겠네
Look! / Okay. Okay.
- 보이죠?
- 그래, 같은 비둘기야
- You see?
- Okay. It's the same pigeon.
근데, 뭐?
So what?
기억 안 나세요? 얘가 희생자의
손 근처에 있던 뭔가를 먹고 있었잖아요
Remember? It was eating something,
from right near the victim's hand.
그리고 다섯 시간이 지난 지금...
And now, five hours later...
죽었어요
It's dead.
그러니까 얘는 중독된 거죠
I think it's been poisoned.
지금 나보고 이 비둘기를
부검해달라고 하는 건가?
You want me to do
an autopsy on the pigeon.
네
Yeah.
왜요? 그게 무슨 의미가 있는데요?
Why? What would that mean?
나도 모르지
I don't know.
하지만 무슨 의미가 있긴 있어요
But it would mean something.
이게 수수께끼의
또 다른 단서일 거예요
It would be another piece of the puzzle.
알겠네
Okey-dokey.
비둘기를 이리 주게
Give me the pigeon.
경위, 실험실에 가져가게
Lieutenant, get that to the lab.
감사합니다
행복한 할로윈 되세요
Thanks. Happy Halloween.
- 아버지는 안 오시는 거야
- 오실 거야
- He's not coming.
- He'll be here.
왜, 왜 전화를 하시곤
나타나지 않으시는 거지?
Why would, why would he call
and not show up?
왜냐면 그게 아버지께서 하려던 거니까
Because that's what he does.
- 관두는 게 좋겠어
- 그렇게 말하지 마
- We're better off.
- Don't say that.
Don't say that!
그렇게 말하지 말라고!
관두자니까!
We're better off!
그렇게 말하지 마!
Don't you say that.
감히 그렇게 말하지 말라고!
Don't you dare say that!
여분 없이 딱 맞게 놓으셨다면서요
Thought you said
you didn't have any extra.
상관없어. 이건 내 거라고
I don't care. It's my candy.
네 문제가 뭔 줄 알아?
You know what your problem is?
넌 결코 기다릴 줄 몰라
You have never learned to wait.
절대로!
Never!
무슨 일이에요?
What's going on?
- 뭐하시는 거예요?
- 아버지 서재를 치워요
- What are you doing?
- Cleaning out his study.
오, 정말. 먼지가 수북하군요
Oh, god, it's so dusty.
그렇죠?
Is it?
몽크 씨...
Mr. Monk...
여보세요
Hello.
네, 경감님. 몽크 씨
Yes, sir. Mr. Monk.
경감님이세요
It's, it's the captain.
여보세요!
Hello!
비둘기에 대한 자네 말이 맞았네
You were right about the pigeon.
그 새는 중독 되었어
The bird was poisoned.
재 부검을 해서 트럭 운전사의
독성 검사를 하게 했는데
I had them go back and do a tox scan
on the armored car driver.
총 맞아 죽기 전에
독에 중독 됐음이 밝혀졌다네
Turns out he had been poisoned too
before he was shot.
- 그 독은...
- 테트라클로로드린요
- The poison was called...
- tetrachlorodrine.
테트라클로로드린이래
아주 치명적이지
Tetrachlorodrine, very deadly.
- 비소보다 더 독하대요
- 비소보다 더 독한 거라네
- Stronger than arsenic.
- It's stronger than arsenic.
실험실에서 막 생산된 걸로
희석되지도 않은 채였어
It came straight from the lab.
It hadn't even been diluted yet.
또 중요한 건, 여기 공장의
관리인과 얘기를 해 봤는데
And get this. We just talked
to the plant manager here.
그 물질이 도난당한 걸로 밝혀졌어
Turns out some of the stuff
had been stolen.
오늘에서야 그 사실을 알았는데
They didn't realize it until today
그걸 도로 제자리에 놓으려던
작자를 잡고 나서 말이야
because they caught
the guy trying to put it back.
잠깐만요. 잠깐만요
제자리에 돌려놨다고요?
Wait. Wait.
He was putting it back?
그래. 그래서 그냥 보내줬대
Yeah, they had to let him go.
그 작자는 모든 사실을 부인했고
증거도 없었으니 말일세
He denied anything and they
didn't have any evidence.
그 작자 이름은...
The guy's name is...
- 길스트랩요
- 길스트랩이래
- Gilstrap.
여기서 컴퓨터 고치는 일로
잠깐씩 근무했다는군
He worked here part time
fixing computers.
길스트랩요?
Gilstrap?
폴 길스트랩요?
Paul Gilstrap?
형!
Ambrose!
형, 캔디 먹지 마!
Ambrose, don't eat the candy!
- 내 돈 주고 산 거야
- 안 돼, 뱉어내
- I paid for it.
- No, spit it out.
뱉어내
독이 있을지도 몰라 / 뭐?
Spit it out.
It could be poisoned? / What?
여태껏 일어났던 일들이
이것과 관련이 있어
That's what this whole thing
has been about.
테트라클로로드린이 주입된 거야
It's been spiked with tetrachlorodrine.
여기 넵튠 바 있어?
Is there a neptune bar in here?
이제 더 없는데
Not anymore there isn't.
오, 맙소사!
나탈리, 911에 전화해줘요 / 맙소사!
Oh, my god!
Natalie, call 911. / My god!
맛이 웃기다고 생각했는데
테트라클로로드린 때문이었어?
Thought it tasted funny.
Tetrachlorodrine?
저 길 아래쪽에 사는 남자가
자기 마누라를 죽이려고 했던 거야
The guy down the street
was trying to kill his wife.
- 너무 늦었어
- 그렇게 말하지 마. 그러지 마
- It's too late.
- Don't say that, don't say that.
일어나. 일어나. 당장!
Just get up, get up now!
- 나탈리, 도와줘요
- 에이드리안, 에이드리안...
- Natalie, help me.
- Adrian. Adrian.
테트라클로로드린은
합성 살충제야
Tetrachlorodrine is
a synthetic insecticide.
나탈리, 도와줘요!
Natalie, help me!
해독제가 없다고
There is no antidote.
난 5분이 지나면 죽을 거야
I'll be dead in five minutes.
에이드리안
Adrian.
- 나 여기 있어. 여기 있다고
- 누가 그랬는지 말해다오
- I'm with you, I'm right here.
- Tell me who did this.
- 그건 중요하지 않아
- 나에겐 중요해
- It doesn't matter.
- It matters to me.
아무것도 모르는 채 죽기는 싫다
I don't want to die without knowing.
말해다오, 에이드리안
Tell me, Adrian.
알겠어
Okay.
이 일을 저지른 사람은...
Here's what happened...
그 사람 이름은 폴 길스트랩이야
his name is Paul Gilstrap.
자기 마누라를 죽이길 원했지
He wanted to kill his wife.
폴은 테트라클로로드린을
만드는 실험실에서 일했어
He worked in a laboratory
where they made tetrachlorodrine.
며칠 전에
A few days ago,
실험실에 몰래 들어가서
테트라클로로드린을 좀 훔쳤대
he snuck in there
and he stole some of it.
형, 나 줄리랑 사탕받기 하다가
Ambrose, I met his wife
그 사람 아내를 만났어
when I went trick-or-treating with Julie.
그런데 그 아내가 말하기를 자기는
매일 자기 전에 넵튠 바를 먹는다는 거야
And she said that she ate a neptune bar
every night before bed.
폴이 그 넵튠 바에 독을 넣은 거지
Gilstrap poisoned her candy.
그런데 하나에만 독을 넣지 않았어
But he couldn't poison just one.
불특정 다수를 노린 연쇄 살인범처럼
보이기를 원했던 거야
He wanted to make it look like
there was a serial killer on the loose,
그래서 여러 개의 다른
넵튠 바에도 독을 넣고는
so he had to poison
a lot of other candy bars.
유통되도록 상점에
도로 갖다 놨지
Put them back into circulation.
그럼 자기 아내는 연쇄 살인범의
또 다른 희생자가 되는 거로군 / 맞아
So his wife would just be
another victim. / That's right.
좋은 계획이네
It's a good plan.
그런데 실수를 저질렀어
But he made a mistake.
잡혀버린 거야
He got caught...
살충제를 도로 갖다놓다가 말이야
trying to put the poison back.
- 모든 게 망한 거네
- 맞아. 모든 게 망한 거야
- Ruined everything.
- That's right. It ruined everything.
그 사람 아내나 그 누구라도
테트라클로로드린 때문에 죽는다면
Because now if his wife or anyone
else died from tetrachlorodrine,
자기가 범인임이 밝혀질 테니까
they'd know it was him.
그래서 필사적이 된 거지
So he was desperate.
자기가 독을 넣은 넵튠 바가
팔려나가기 전에 회수해야 했던 거야
He had to get all of the poisoned
candy bars out of circulation.
- 두 개만 빼고 다 찾았군
- 그렇지
- He found them all except for two.
- Right.
트럭 운전사가 먹던 게 그 하나였어
The armored car driver had one.
이미 먹어버렸지
He had already taken a bite.
운전사가 갑자기 죽어버리면
If the driver just dropped dead,
부검이 행해질 거란 걸
길스트랩은 알았지
Gilstrap knew there'd be an autopsy.
재빨리 대책을 생각해냈어
So he had to think fast.
운전사의 총을 꺼내서
여러 번 그를 쏴댄 거지
He grabbed the driver's gun
and shot him repeatedly.
누가 총을 다섯 번이나
맞고 죽은 사람을
Who would bother looking for poison
독살당했을지도 모른다고 의심하겠어?
in a guy who had been shot five times?
그럼 하나의 넵튠 바만 남았던 거네
Which left just one candy bar.
내가 먹은 그거 말이야
The one I ate.
맞아
That's right.
폴은 밤새 내내 그 넵튠 바를
회수하려고 노력했던 거야
He's been trying
to get it back all night.
얼마나 남았어요?
How much further?
20블록쯤요
20 blocks.
에이드리안, 미안해
Adrian, I'm sorry.
- 미안해
- 무슨 소리 하는 거야?
- I'm sorry.
- What are you talking about?
아버지 말이야
Dad.
- 오, 아니야
- 내가 아버질 떠나게 했어
- Oh, no.
- I drove him away.
아냐 / 내가 아버지를
떠나게 만든 거야
No. / He couldn't stand me.
아니야 / 아버진 날
견딜 수 없으셨던 거야, 에이드리안
- No.
- He couldn't stand me, Adrian.
- 내 실수라니까
- 아냐, 미안해
- It was my fault.
- No, I'm sorry.
나 때문이었어
It was me.
넌 좋은 동생이었어, 에이드리안
You're a good brother, Adrian.
사랑한다
I love you.
울지 마, 에이드리안
Don't cry, Adrian.
이제 강해져야 해
Be strong now.
거기 넵튠 바 하나 더 있네요?
That another neptune bar?
형이 먹었던 넵튠 바
포장지 어디 있어요?
Where's the wrapper
from the one he ate?
여기요
It's right here.
뭐야?
What?
뭔데?
이건 유통기한이 11개월이나 지났어
This one expired 11 months ago.
이게 작년에 딱 하나 남았다던
그건가 봐
That must be the candy bar
left over from last year.
작년 할로윈 거라고?
From last Halloween?
그래서 맛이 웃겼던 거로군
That's why it tasted funny.
그래서 맛이 웃겼던 거야
그럼 이게...
So this...
이게 바로 그 독이
들어있는 나머지 하나지
This is the, this is the poison.
그래서 맛이 웃겼던 거야
That's why it tasted funny.
그래서 맛이 웃겼던 거라고!
That's why it tasted funny!
이게 바로...
This is the...
이게 바로 독이 들어있는
나머지 하나였어
This is the one with poison.
아, 나, 복통이었던 거야
I had, I had a stomachache.
미안해
I'm sorry.
모두를 당황하게 해서 말이야
Everyone got so upset.
폴 길스트랩?
Paul Gilstrap?
이런, 하나 놓쳤더군요
Boo. You missed one.
앰브로즈 씨, 우리 데이트 말인데요
Ambrose, about our date.
금요일 어때요?
Is Friday okay?
아녜요, 나탈리. 괜찮아요
No, Natalie. That's okay.
그럴 필요 없어요
내가 죽는다고 생각했던 거잖아요
You don't have to.
You thought I was dying.
금요일에 여기 올게요
I'll be here Friday.
어, 보세요
여기 쪽지가 있어요
Hey, look. There's a note.
'들렀다 간다'
Stopped by.
'아무도 없더구나'
Nobody home.
'나무랄 순 없겠지
나라도 안 기다렸을 거다'
Can't blame you.
I wouldn't wait for me either.
아버지야
Dad.
추신
P.S.
'앰브로즈, 네가 집 밖으로 나와서
자랑스럽구나'
Ambrose, I'm proud of you
for getting out of the house.
내가 자랑스러우시대?
He said he was proud of me?
다시 오실까?
You think he'll be back?
모르겠어
I don't know.
다시 오실 거야
I think he'll be back.
음, 우리는 아마...
Maybe we should, uh,
안으로 들어가야겠군요
go inside.
집안으로 들어갑시다
Let's go inside.
집안이 더 편하거든요
It's better, inside.
잠깐 비켜줄래?
Excuse me.
자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)